

Adarsh

DATA ANALYST

I am presently designated as Data Analyst with TATA Consultancy Services Pvt. Ltd., for nearly 4 years started as System Analyst and then migrated to Data Analyst till the current date.

4 YEARS

DATA ANALYST

Tata Consultancy Services

09/2017 - Present, Bangalore

Achievements/Tasks

- Data Analyst with nearly 4 years of experience in Data Science & Machine Learning on GCP Platform which also includes covering networks, data centers, servers, storage systems and databases, security, and cloud technologies.
- Imparted training & mentored individuals on Google Cloud Platform atTCS.
- I have worked in Data Engineering which includes handling of Big data using Big Query and worked on python codes in preprocessing of data.
- Good in handling complex queries of a big query while transforming data into GCP.
- Skilled in management of technology service areas of GCP Platform which enables the management of many complex business processes to seamlessly optimize in transferring data from insights to GCP.
- Insightful knowledge of Python and Machine Learning Using Python
 - which used to solve complex scenarios.
- As a part of the Administrator team for Citi North America region, handled the UI and backend changes to all controlled environments and production.
- Established the team during the migration from one location to another with proper process flow and provided KT to keep the business SLA on track along with smooth and

fast operations.

Many appreciation emails from clients for resolving their critical issues within the downtime of business delivery, and performed many miscellaneous tasks like load balancing of data, migration of backup clients, & so on



Full Professional Proficiency

Tableau for dashboard creating

Full Professional Proficiency

EXCEL, Google-sheets, Tableau for Data Visualization *Full Professional Proficiency*

TOOLS

SKILLS

Python

SOFT-SKILLS

GCP Big-Query Tableau Power Bl
Detail-oriented, thorough, and vigilant to collect all
necessary data without missing critical components.
Python - Jupyter, Visual Code EMC Networker

Sloidled tentle ostanding and idated analytic lent perfecentively o intemperate following sindings and them the keeps consist of end used a general.

Creative in putting together projections for a variety of scenarios to assist departmental experts in making future decisions regarding the organization's growth.

Technologically-savvy to assist end users with understanding technology, software updates, and changes to existing protocols.



WORK EXPERIENCE

IT Operations Analyst - SAP MS(Mumbai/Bangalore) - Tata Consultancy Services (12/2017 - 08/2018)

- This includes covering networks, data centers, servers, storage systems and databases, security, and cloud technologies.
- Handled the internal business Systems and client systems like Nestle, Under- Armour, Bayern Munich, Kingfisher etc. based out of America, Australia, Iraqetc.
- Python is used in scripting to minimize the workaround in securing and keeping the backup of the client on the backup server.
- Managing resource planning for new Networker servers and performing multiple Network Server set up
 Supporting more than 60,000 backup clients with different databases like SAP HANA, MAXDB, SYBASE, and MS-SQL
- Monitoring high severity issues such as backup server down, critical backup failures and restores as well as restoring the data as requested by the customer on an urgent basis if there is any issue in any of the clientserver.
- Worked across 2 different teams with varied profiles(HEC -Run Team and Cloud Services).
- Performed backup restore analysis from server to system and system to system and created dashboard according to given details and prepared detailed analysis of the same.
- Automating backup configuration scripts to adapt to the newly established S4HANA and Google Cloud systems.
- Documenting all latest changes to process and creating new process documents.
- Managing and monitoring team members as Shift lead and ensuring equal work assignment.

DATA ANALYST - Woolworths Group - Tata Consultancy Services (09/2018 - Present)

- This project has the working of data engineering in which the data from the insights has to be transformed to Google Cloud Platform (GCP) using connectivity as Python and SQL as Google Big Query used in transforming data to GCP platform.
- converted data into actionable insights by predicting and modeling future Outcomes.
- Collected and analyzed data as per the requirements of the customer and transform it into the Google cloud.
- Created visually impactful dashboards in Excel and Tableau for data reporting by using Tableau. Extracted, interpreted, and analyzed data to identify key metrics and transform raw data into meaningful, actionable information.
- Present detailed reports about the meaning of gathered data to members of management and help them identify



scenarios utilizing modifications in the data.

- Using Python, SQL, and Excel developed the reports for a Insights sales of the given Woolworths customer.
- Built out the data and reporting infrastructure from the ground up using Tableau and SQL to provide real-time insights into the product, marketing funnels, and business KPIs.

EDUCATION

B.E

Siddaganga Institute of Technology

08/2013 - 06/2017,

Tumkur, 8.79 CGPA

Courses

Electrical & Electronics Engineering

M.Tech

PES University

10/2020 - Present,

Courses

Data Science & MachineLearning Bangalore